# Siddaharth Suman

Software Engineer III

### **Objectives**

Looking for a continuous learning environment and professional growth in an organization where my skills are adequately utilized.

I wish to contribute the skills that I have learned over the years for the betterment of the organization.

#### **About Me**

I am a Software Engineer III with total experience of 5.5 years and currently working with FactSet Systems India Pvt Ltd. I am a self-motivated and adaptable kind of individual who yearns to get his hands on the latest trends in technology. I am a quick learner and a team player who is neither afraid to take lead nor afraid to ask for help in case I get stuck

I possess good communication, interpersonal, and leadership skills and can effectively deal with teammates and clients. I am always willing to help others in need and motivate them and boost their morale.

I like to work as a team and look forward to working with teams where I can contribute with my expertise as well as learn

### **Experience**

### Dec 2018 -Present

### Software Engineer III

FactSet Systems India Pvt. Ltd.

- · Worked on endpoint development for simple access to company's dataset
- Worked on importing of data provided by suppliers and integrated them into the company's dataset
- Worked on the company's financial data tool used by banks and financial institutions

### Dec 2015 - Dec 2018

### Senior System Engineer

Infosys Ltd.

- · Worked on web applications and mobile applications
- · Worked on development of automated tools and perform testing of web applications
- · Provided middleware support

### Aug 2015 - Oct 2015

#### Assistant Professor

Institute of Forensic Science

- · Worked as a faculty for the institute
- Taught the subject of Cyber Forensics and Offenses

#### May 2014 - Oct 2014

### Freelancer

Palmate Solutions

· Worked as a Backend Web Developer

#### Jan 2014 - Mar 2014

#### Intern TechMeet

· Worked as an Android Application Developer

#### Jun 2013 - Oct 2013

Opine Solutions

· Worked as an Android Application Developer

#### **Projects**

### **Endpoint** development

Technologies: Javascript, NodeJS

### Team Size: 3

- · Endpoint development for ease of use by clients to request company's dataset and query them
- · Users can alternatively use UI to perform queries and get results as well
- · Worked on three such endpoints and received appreciation by the team
- · Received 2 awards for the project

#### Data Importer

Technologies: Oracle SQL

Team Size: 2

- Package used to import data provided by suppliers to integrate into the company's dataset
- Package is run periodically via cron jobs and automatically generates reports

### Financial data tool

Technologies: Java, Php, WixToolset, Msi

#### Team Size: 5

- · Standalone product used by banks and financial institutions
- · Worked as acting lead on the project and ensured timely delivery of tasks and resolution of issues
- Worked on creation of custom Java packages and Msi packages
- · Worked on migration from Teamcity to Jenkins and performing build automations and deployments
- · Received award for the project

#### Personal Info

#### Phone

+91 9920760964

#### E-mail

siddaharthsuman@gmail.com

#### Date of birth

December 18, 1993

#### Marital Status

Unmarried

#### Github

github.com/SiddaharthSuman

### Frontend Technologies/ **Frameworks**

- Angular
- · Vue.js
- Bulma
- Bootstrap
- · Java Swing
- JavaFX

## **Backend Technologies/ Frameworks**

- Node.js
- Php
- Servlets

### **Mobile Technologies**

Android

### Markup and Scripting Languages

- HTMI
- JavaScript
- CSS
- · jQuery
- Php

### **Programming Languages**

- Java
- Typescript
- C++
- · Python

# **Testing Frameworks and Tools**

- Selenium
- · Katalon Studio HP UFT
- Coded UI

# **Databases**

- MySQL
- MSSQL
- MongoDB

# **Version Control**

• Git

SVN

# **Tools**

TeamCity

Jenkins

#### **IDEs and Editors**

- Eclipse
- Visual Studio Code
- Atom
- · Android Studio
- Sublime Text

### **Operating Systems**

- Windows
- Mac OS
- Linux

### Partner Assessment

Portal

Technologies: Angular 5, Bulma, CSS, HTML, Javascript, Typescript

- Team Size: 8
   Portal for partners of the firm to be assessed on their performance and get recommendation for
- salary changes

  Superiors can see a partner's summary, history and other information
- · Superiors can provide a salary recommendation for partners based on their assessment
- · Worked directly with client

### Profile and Rewards Web Application

**Technologies:** Angular 4, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, jQuery, Javascript, Typescript **Team Size:** 12

- Employee centric dashboard with various reports and details of the employee
- Employees can generate their compensation, health and time off related reports
- · Received appreciation from teammates and onsite team as well for good performance

### Geofence and Custom Plugin for Workspace Reservation

Technologies: Android, Ionic, Cordova

Team Size: 10

- · Application for employees for reserving workspaces in their office
- Employees can reserve workspaces on a temporary or regular basis as well
- Employees can schedule reservation for future dates and can automatically get a reservation as soon as entering the work area

### MobileIron Downloads Report Tool

**Technologies:** Selenium, JavaFX, Apache POI, MobileIron, Microsoft Excel, PhantomJS **Team Size:** 1

- · Automation tool that generates reports for 80+ production applications
- · Enables employees to work on other tasks and not be blocked on creating report manually
- · Manual report generation blocks an employee for 1 hour and is prone to human errors
- The tool takes under 5 minutes to generate the report and is accurate every time
- · Received appreciation from offshore as well as onshore team for simplicity and time saving

### PwC Application Details Portal

**Technologies:** Angular 4, Php, Servlets, Google Drive, Soap **Team Size:** 1

- Portal for details of applications supported by the support team
- Gives access to internal details of 26+ applications across many territories
- Facility to manage applications list, ping application's soap services and manage relevant documents using integrated Google Drive support
- Performs automatic healthcheck for all the applications
- · Received appreciation from team

### Infosys Buy/Sell App for Android

Technologies: Android, Php, MySQL

- Team Size: 5
- · App for a buy/sell platform
- Users can post items for selling and can also see other posts
- · Users can show interest in an item for sale and contact the seller

### **Education**

#### Sep 2011 - May 2015

#### Atharva College of Engineering, Mumbai University, BE in Computer Engineering, 2015

- Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" for EXTC faculties
- Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" for CMPN and INFT faculties
- Conducted Training and Placement Session on "C++" for final year students
- Held the posts of Assistant Technical Head and Technical Head for Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Java Primer" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Backend Web Development" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Organised Google Dev Fest for Google Developer's Group

till Mar 2011

#### Kendriya Vidyalaya INS Hamla, Mumbai

#### **Publications**

Feb 2015

Supercharging web applications with Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-1 Feb 2015)

Jun 2015

Information system using Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-3 June 2015)

### Languages

- English
- Marathi
- Hindi